Inventory of the Davison Art Rooms Exhibition Catalogs Collection, 1928 - 1949
Davison Art Rooms Exhibition Catalogs Collection, 1928 - 1949
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)
1000-45
0.25
1
The Davison Art Rooms were created at the opening of Olin Memorial Library in 1928 as a tribute to George W. (Wesleyan class of 1892) and Harriet Baldwin Davison. The Davison Art Rooms were closed and their contents transferred to the newly-constructed Davison Art Center for its opening in 1952.
This collection contains exhibition catalogs and exhibition lists from the Davison Art Rooms from the years 1928 to 1949.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Acquired by Olin Library.
Historical Note
The Davison Art Rooms were created at the opening of Olin Memorial Library in 1928 as a tribute to George W. (Wesleyan class of 1892) and Harriet Baldwin Davison. Three rooms on the south side of the third floor of Olin Library were dedicated to the exhibition of prints and works of art. The Davisons had gradually and quietly begun donating parts of their print collection to the university at this time, and these gifts formed the basis of some of the first exhibitions of the Davison Art Rooms.
Collection Overview
This collection contains exhibition catalogs and exhibition lists from the Davison Art Rooms from the years 1928 to 1949.
Collection Arrangement
Arrangement is chronological.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Davison Art Center.; Davison, Harriet R. Baldwin; Davison, George W. (George Willets), b. 1872.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Alumni and alumnae.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.). Library--Exhibitions.; Art --Exhibitions.; Prints --United States --20th century --Exhibitions.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - 1928-1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Loan Exhibition of Paintings and Etchings. May 17 – June 18, 1928.
    - Loan Exhibition of Fine Prints by Dürer and Rembrandt from the Collection of Mr. & Mrs. George W. Davison. May 17 – June 18, 1928.
    - Exhibits, Olin Memorial Library. May 21 – June 2. June 14, 15, 16, [1929].
    - Art Exhibitions at Wesleyan University: Lectures and Announcements. 1933-1934.
    - Includes Roman Baroque Church Facades. November 15 – December 1, 1933.
    - The Urban Vernacular of the Thirties, Forties, and Fifties: American Cities Before the Civil War. Photographs by Berenice Abbott. 1934.
    - Romanesque Churches of Apulia: Photographs from the Kingsley Porter Collection. November 1934.
    - Wesleyan University Architectural Exhibitions: French Houses of the Early Fifteenth Century. June 1935. Catalog by Henry-Russell Hitchcock.
    - Landscape Prints: Four Exhibitions of Prints Loaned from the Collection of Mr. & Mrs. George W. Davison: I. October 15 - November 15, 1937.
    - Catalog of paintings by Lilla Cabot Perry. November 7 – December 6, 1937.
    - Prints of Architecture: Four Exhibitions of Prints Loaned from the Collection of Mr. & Mrs. George W. Davison: II. December, 1937.
    - Wesleyan Print Collection: Commencement 1938: 500 Years of Prints. 1938.
    - Wesleyan Print Collection: Contemporary American and European Prints from the Collection and a Loan. October 13, 1938.
    - Loan Exhibition of Watercolors from a Selection of Fine Arts of the United States Treasury Department. November 2-15, 1938.
    - Wesleyan Print Collection: Fifteenth and Sixteenth Century Engravings, Woodcuts, Etchings. December, 1938.
  - 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Etchings by Rembrandt and his Contemporaries. January, 1939.
    - Loan Exhibition of Etchings and Drawings by John Taylor Arms. April, 1939.
    - Wesleyan Print Collection: Exhibition of Prints by Whistler and His Contemporaries. Commencement, 1939.
    - Wadsworth Antheneum: Prints of the Seventeenth Century. 1939.
    - Loan Exhibition of Modern and Old Prints. Commencement, 1940.
    - Significant Prints: Old and Modern. October, 1940.
  - 1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Prints by Goya and his Contemporaries. February, 1941.
    - Drypoints by Philip Kappel. May 16-30, 1941.
    - Prints by Rembrandt and Whistler: A Comparative Exhibition. Commencement, 1941.
    - Paintings and Prints by Russell T. Limbach. Until October 13th [1941].
    - Engravings and Etchings by William Hogarth. Until November 5th, 1941.
  - 1942-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Etching Since the Sixteenth Century. February, 1942.
    - Oil Paintings and Watercolors, Bill Darr. April, 1942.
    - A Gift of Prints in Honor of George W. Davison. Commencement, 1942.
    - A Collector’s Favorite Prints: Selections from the Wesleyan Print Collection. [Selected by George W. Davison]. Commencement, 1942.
    - Contemporary British Prints. October 3 – November 8, 1942.
    - Sea Paintings by Frederick J. Waugh, N. A. from the Collection of Mr. & Mrs. Ernest E. Quantell. June, July, 1945.
    - The Wesleyan University Print Collection [catalogue of holdings]. May, 1949.